Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1849-2008; Series I
  - Correspondence
    - Whitney, John Hay
      - Yale University
        - Summer High School, 1964-1965 (Box 55, Folder 3)
        - University Library, French books, 1962-1981 (Box 55, Folder 4-5)
        - Yale Alumni Fund, reunions, 1965-1976 (Box 55, Folder 6)
        - Yale University Press
          - Gifts to, 1930-1954 (Box 55, Folder 7)
          - John Hay Whitney Fund, 1945-1981 (Box 55, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous, 1947-1976 (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
      - Yeshiva University honorary degree, 1957 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Zuckerman, Lord Solly, 1964-1978 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Topical
    - Ambassadorial files
      - Correspondence
        - Accommodations, 1956-1957 (Box 56, Folder 5)
        - Congratulations on ambassadorship
          - A-M, 1956-1957 (Box 57, Folder 1-13)
          - N-Z, 1956-1957 (Box 58, Folder 1-10)
        - Departure, 1961 (Box 59, Folder 1)
        - Gifts, 1963-1969 (Box 59, Folder 2)
          Exchanges between Whitney and British officials about which official gifts will remain in England after his tenure as ambassador ends.
        - Personal, 1958-1961 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
        - Private, 1956-1960 (Box 59, Folder 5)
        - Secretary, 1957-1961 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Speeches
        Arranged chronologically.
        - Speech list, 1957-1962 (Box 60, Folder 1)
        - Arrival at London Airport, 1957 February 24 (Box 60, Folder 2)
        - American Women's Activities, Columbia Club, 1957 March 13 (Box 60, Folder 3)
        - Pilgrim's Dinner, Savoy Hotel, 1957 April 4 (Box 60, Folder 4)
        - Presentation of Community Relations certificate, 1957 April 26 (Box 60, Folder 5)
        - American Chamber of Commerce, 1957 April 30 (Box 60, Folder 6)
        - Anglo-American Parliamentary Group, 1957 May 13 (Box 60, Folder 7)
        - British Industries Fair, 1957 May 16 (Box 60, Folder 8)
        - Fulbright Commission reception, 1957 May 17 (Box 60, Folder 9)
        - Atlantic Community, English Speaking Union, 1957 June 4 (Box 60, Folder 10)
        - Junior Carleton Club, 1957 June 13 (Box 60, Folder 11)
        - American Society dinner, 1957 July 4 (Box 60, Folder 12)
        - Variety Club luncheon, 1957 July 9 (Box 60, Folder 13)
        - Welcome luncheon, 1957 July 15 (Box 60, Folder 14)
        - American Bar Association, 1957 July 26 (Box 60, Folder 15)
        - Blackpool "lighting up" ceremony, 1957 September 6 (Box 60, Folder 16)
        - Golden Laurel award, 1957 September 8 (Box 60, Folder 17)
        - Cardiff Business Club and English Speaking Union, 1957 October 7 (Box 60, Folder 18)
        - Bexley Chamber of Commerce, 1957 November 6 (Box 60, Folder 19)
        - Oxford University American Association, 1957 November 15 (Box 60, Folder 20)
        - American Society Thanksgiving dinner, 1957 November 28 (Box 60, Folder 21)
        - Yorkshire visit, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 22)
        - Imperial Defense College, 1958 February 3 (Box 60, Folder 23)
        - St. David's Day dinner, 1958 March 1 (Box 60, Folder 24)
        - Coventry Chamber of Commerce, 1958 March 11 (Box 60, Folder 25)
        - Norwich visit, 1958 April 10 (Box 60, Folder 26)
        - British Industry ceremony, 1958 April 22 (Box 60, Folder 27)
        - City Livery club, 1958 April 24 (Box 60, Folder 28)
        - Unveiling of plaque at Plymouth, 1958 May 14 (Box 60, Folder 29)
        - Mayoral banquet, Salisbury, 1958 May 19 (Box 60, Folder 30)
        - Thirty Club, 1958 May 20 (Box 60, Folder 31)
        - Cambridge visit, 1958 May 23 (Box 60, Folder 32)
        - Felsted School, 1958 June 13 (Box 60, Folder 33)
        - Livery banquet, 1958 June 25 (Box 60, Folder 34)
        - American Society, 1958 July 4 (Box 60, Folder 35)
        - Portland, Nautilus, 1958 August 12 (Box 60, Folder 36)
        - English Speaking Union, Edinburgh, 1958 August 29 (Box 60, Folder 37)
        - Civic lunch, Belfast City Hall, 1958 September 29 (Box 60, Folder 38)
        - Stormont, 1958 September 30 (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - Civic lunch, Londonderry, 1958 October 1 (Box 61, Folder 2)
        - United States Navy awards, 1958 October 3 (Box 61, Folder 3)
        - Royal Commonwealth Society, 1958 October 9 (Box 61, Folder 4)
        - Clubland, American stone unveiling, 1958 October 10 (Box 61, Folder 5)
        - Institute of Directors, Sheffield, 1958 November 3 (Box 61, Folder 6)
        - Community Relations awards ceremony, 1958 November 5 (Box 61, Folder 7)
        - Westminster Chamber of Commerce, 1958 November 20 (Box 61, Folder 8)
        - Thanksgiving Day televised talk, 1958 November 27 (Box 61, Folder 9)
        - Dollar Exports Council, 1958 December 5 (Box 61, Folder 10)
        - United and Cecil Club, 1958 December 9 (Box 61, Folder 11)
        - British Broadcasting Company television interview, 1959 February 12 (Box 61, Folder 12)
        - English Speaking Union, Birmingham, 1959 February 26 (Box 61, Folder 13)
        - Lloyd's Golf Club dinner, 1959 March 11 (Box 61, Folder 14)
        - Edinburgh Press Club, 1959 April 11 (Box 61, Folder 15)
        - Southampton Chamber of Commerce, 1959 April 24 (Box 61, Folder 16)
        - Columbia Club, London, 1959 April 27 (Box 61, Folder 17)
        - British-American Parliamentary Association, 1959 April 27 (Box 61, Folder 18)
        - Presentation of the Ambassador's Cup, 1959 May 6 (Box 61, Folder 19)
        - Manchester Chamber of Commerce, English Speaking Union, 1959 May 28 (Box 61, Folder 20)
        - Corporation of Manchester, 1959 May 29 (Box 61, Folder 21)
        - Press Association, 1959 June 10 (Box 61, Folder 22)
        - Royal Geographical Society, 1959 June 15 (Box 61, Folder 23)
        - Rotary Club of London, 1959 June 24 (Box 61, Folder 24)
        - American Society Dinner, 1959 July 3 (Box 61, Folder 25)
        - Scottish Industries Exhibition luncheon, 1959 September 7 (Box 61, Folder 26)
        - Ancient and Honorable Artillery Company of Massachusetts, 1959 October 5 (Box 61, Folder 27)
        - English-Speaking Union, Liverpool, 1959 October 20 (Box 61, Folder 28)
        - Mayfair Association lunch, 1959 October 21 (Box 61, Folder 29)
        - Sir Walter Raleigh statue unveiling, 1959 October 27 (Box 61, Folder 30)
        - English-Speaking Union, Brighton-Hove, 1959 November 3 (Box 61, Folder 31)
        - Oxford University Law Society, 1959 November 6 (Box 61, Folder 32)
        - Community Relations awards reception, 1959 November 18 (Box 61, Folder 33)
        - American Society dinner, Thanksgiving Proclamation, 1959 November 26 (Box 61, Folder 34)
        - West Indies conference, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Leeds Chamber of Commerce, 1960 February 11 (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - Institute of Metals, 1960 March 31 (Box 62, Folder 3)
        - Consular conference, 1960 April 4 (Box 62, Folder 4)
        - Portsmouth Chamber of Commerce, 1960 April 28 (Box 62, Folder 5)
        - Martha Deane interview, 1960 May 3 (Box 62, Folder 6)
        - Commonwealth Correspondents' Assocation, 1960 June 2 (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - American Society Dinner, 1960 July 4 (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - American Battle Monuments Commission, 1960 July 20-21 (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - Presentation Folger Shakespeare (residence), 1960 September 8 (Box 62, Folder 10)
        - Birmingham Consular Assocation lunch, 1960 September 30 (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - English Speaking Union, 1960 October 5 (Box 62, Folder 12)
        - Luncheon of the American Chamber of Commerce in London, 1960 October 6 (Box 62, Folder 13)
        - Society of Merchant Ventures, 1960 October 14 (Box 62, Folder 14)
        - Embassy Orientation, 1960 October 18 (Box 62, Folder 15)
        - Remarks to the Company of Skinners, 1960 October 18 (Box 62, Folder 16)
        - American Women's Club, 1960 October 27 (Box 62, Folder 17)
        - Printers' Pension, 1960 November 2 (Box 62, Folder 18)
        - Monday Luncheon Club, 1960 November 14 (Box 62, Folder 19)
        - American Society, 1960 November 24 (Box 62, Folder 20)
        - Community Relations Awards, 1961 January 10 (Box 62, Folder 21)
        - Farewell address, Pilgrims Dinner, 1961 January 11 (Box 62, Folder 22)
        - AAAA - White Sulphur Springs, 1961 April 21 (Box 62, Folder 23)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Accommodations, London, 1956-1957 (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - Alphabetical list of congratulatory letters, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 2)
        - Announcement of appointment, 1956 (Box 63, Folder 3)
        - Christmas, cards and gift lists, 1956-1957 (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - The Diplomatist yearbook, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 5)
        - Event programs, 1957-1960 (Box 63, Folder 6)
        - Medals held, Circa 1961 (Box 63, Folder 7)
        - NBC interview, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 8)
        - Office procedures, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 9)
        - Pilgrims Dinner, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 10)
        - West Indies, 1960-1961 (Box 63, Folder 11-12)
    - Fine Art collection
      Where noted, folders contain catalog cards with fields for information on artists, title, provenance, value, medium, date, size, description, exhibitions, and literature. Not all fields are filled in.
      - General (mostly correspondence), 1930-1997, undated (Box 64, Folder 1-46)
        Includes receipts for insurance for lending paintings to museums, correspondence with their dealer about new purchases, and with graduate students and researchers about visiting the collection for research, as well as inquiries about purchasing Van Gogh's self-portrait.
      - Appraisals
        - General
          - 1955-1997 (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
          - 1998 (Box 66, Folder 1)
        - Fishers Island, New York; Saratoga Springs, New York; St. James's Place, London, United Kingdom, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 1)
        - Greentree, Manhasset, New York, paintings, drawings, prints and sculpture, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 2)
        - New York City locations, miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 3)
        - One Beekman Place, New York, New York, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Artists
        - Alexander, Francis, 1930-1990 (Box 68, Folder 1)
        - Alken, Henry, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - Appleton, John, 1954-1961 (Box 68, Folder 3)
        - Austin, Darrel, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 4)
        - Bazille, Frédéric, 1960-1998 (Box 68, Folder 5)
        - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1960-1998 (Box 68, Folder 6)
        - Bellows, George, 1927-1984 (Box 68, Folder 7-8)
        - Berman, Eugene, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 9)
        - Blake, William, 1954-1983 (Box 68, Folder 10)
        - Bombois, Camille, 1958-1959 (Box 68, Folder 11)
        - Boucher, François, 1944-1969 (Box 68, Folder 12)
        - Boudin, Eugène, 1958-1983 (Box 68, Folder 13)
        - Braque, Georges, 1952-1983 (Box 68, Folder 14)
        - Brize, Cornelius, 1947-1986 (Box 68, Folder 15)
        - Brush, George, 1947-1986 (Box 68, Folder 16)
        - Cals, Adolphe-Felix, 1958 (Box 68, Folder 17)
        - Cassatt, Mary, 1958-1992 (Box 68, Folder 18)
        - Cézanne, Paul, 1952-1996 (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
        - Chamberlain, Samuel, 1934 (Box 69, Folder 4)
        - Chardin, Jean Baptiste Siméon, 1958-1982 (Box 69, Folder 5)
        - Chassériau, Théodore, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 6)
        - Churchill, John S., 1958 (Box 69, Folder 7)
        - Collins, Ann, 1953 (Box 69, Folder 8)
        - Copley, John Singleton, 1930, 1946 (Box 69, Folder 9)
        - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille, 1952-2000 (Box 69, Folder 10)
        - Courbet, Gustave, 1954-1983 (Box 69, Folder 11)
        - Cross, Henri, 1950-1992 (Box 69, Folder 12)
        - Cushing, Lily, 1955 (Box 69, Folder 13)
        - Daumier, Honoré, 1960-1983 (Box 69, Folder 14)
        - Degas, Edgar
          - General, 1945-1993 (Box 69, Folder 15)
          - Avant la Course, 1928-1989 (Box 69, Folder 16)
          - Cheval de Selle and Le Faux Depart, 1960-1993 (Box 70, Folder 1)
          - Chevaux de Course, self portrait, 1928-2000 (Box 70, Folder 2)
          - Le Promenade des Chevaux, 1962-1998 (Box 70, Folder 3)
        - De La Fresnaye, Roger, 1951, 1984, 1992 (Box 70, Folder 4)
        - Derain, André, 1931-1984 (Box 70, Folder 5)
        - Devis, Arthur, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 6)
        - Dreux, Alfred, 1956-1989 (Box 70, Folder 7)
        - Di Verdura, Fulco, 1955-1956 (Box 70, Folder 8)
        - Dufy, Raoul, 1951-1989 (Box 70, Folder 9)
        - Eakins, Thomas, 1954-1959 (Box 70, Folder 10)
        - Earl, T. P., 1930-1989 (Box 70, Folder 11)
        - Edzard, Dietz, 1930 (Box 70, Folder 12)
        - Epstein (sculptor), 1931 (Box 71, Folder 1)
        - Etty, William, 1959 (Box 71, Folder 2)
        - Fantin-Latour, Henri, 1957-1961 (Box 71, Folder 3)
        - Feininger, Theodore Lux, 1949 (Box 71, Folder 4)
        - Ferneley, John E., 1930 (Box 71, Folder 5)
        - Field, Erastus, 1959-1976 (Box 71, Folder 6)
        - Flint, W. Russell, 1931 (Box 71, Folder 7)
        - Forain, Jean Louis, 1931-1982 (Box 71, Folder 8)
        - Fosburgh, James, 1953-1979 (Box 71, Folder 9)
        - Frank, Frederick, 1951 (Box 71, Folder 10)
        - Fraser, James Earle, 1951 (Box 71, Folder 11)
        - French, Daniel C., 1959 (Box 71, Folder 12)
        - Ganso, Emil, 1946 (Box 71, Folder 13)
        - Gauguin, Paul, 1950-1960 (Box 71, Folder 14)
        - Géricault, Théodore, 1958-2000 (Box 71, Folder 15)
        - González, Eva, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 16)
        - Gris, Juan, 1971-1985 (Box 71, Folder 17)
        - Guglielmi, Louis, 1947 (Box 71, Folder 18)
        - Harlow, George, 1914 (Box 71, Folder 19)
        - Harnett, William Michael, 1961-1984 (Box 71, Folder 20)
        - Haseltine, Herbert, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 21)
        - Herring, John Frederkick Senior, 1930-1931 (Box 71, Folder 21)
        - Hill, J. W. (John William), 1961-1984 (Box 71, Folder 22)
        - Homer, Winslow, 1955-1982 (Box 71, Folder 23)
        - Hopper, Edward, 1949-1983 (Box 71, Folder 24)
        - Hovey, Charles Mason, 1994 (Box 71, Folder 25)
        - Ingres, Jean-Auguste-Dominique, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 26)
        - Ipsen, Ernest L., 1931 (Box 71, Folder 27)
        - Isenburger, Eric, 1947 (Box 71, Folder 28)
        - Jansen, Johan, 1958 (Box 71, Folder 29)
        - Jouett, Matthew H., 1942-1957 (Box 71, Folder 30)
        - Keene, Paul F., 1955 (Box 71, Folder 31)
        - King, William D., 1950-1962 (Box 71, Folder 32)
        - Klein, Samuel C., 1934 (Box 72, Folder 1)
        - Klossowsky, Balthasar (Balthus), 1949, 1956, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 2)
        - Knoop, Guitou, 1939 (Box 72, Folder 3)
        - Koerner, Henry, 1949-1954 (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1947-1954 (Box 72, Folder 5)
        - LaFarge, John (artist), 1978 (Box 72, Folder 6)
        - Lavery, John, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 7)
        - Lawrence, Jacob, 1960-1997 (Box 72, Folder 8)
        - Lee, Doris, 1950-1951 (Box 72, Folder 9)
        - Levine, Jack, 1947-1953 (Box 72, Folder 10)
        - Lewis, John Frederick, 1958-1988 (Box 72, Folder 11)
        - Linthorst, L., 1931 (Box 72, Folder 12)
        - Maillol, Aristide, 1954-1976 (Box 72, Folder 13)
        - Manet, Édouard, 1945-2000 (Box 72, Folder 14-15)
        - Marshall, Benjamin, 1929-1988 (Box 72, Folder 16)
        - Matisse, Henri, 1949-1984 (Box 72, Folder 17-18)
        - Marquet, Albert, 1971-1975 (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - McMein, Neysa, 1934 (Box 73, Folder 2)
        - Meza, Guillermo, 1945 (Box 73, Folder 3)
        - Miller, Charles H., 1950-1951 (Box 73, Folder 4)
        - Miró, Joan, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 5)
        - Monet, Claude, 1946-1997 (Box 73, Folder 6-8)
        - Moore, Henry, 1966-1968 (Box 73, Folder 9)
        - Morisot, Berthe, 1948-1989 (Box 73, Folder 10)
        - Mortimer, John Hamilton, 1950-1988 (Box 73, Folder 11)
        - Mote, G. W., 1958-1959 (Box 73, Folder 12)
        - Munnings, Alfred J., 1948-1989 (Box 73, Folder 13-14)
        - Music, Antonio, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 15)
        - Palmer, James Lynwood, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 16)
        - Parrish, Maxfield, 1946-1984 (Box 73, Folder 17)
        - Perlin, Bernard, 1949-1957 (Box 74, Folder 1)
        - Picasso, Pablo
          - General, 1947-1992 (Box 74, Folder 2-8)
          - Gertrude Stein Collection, 1968-1974 (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
            Includes an agreement between David and Nelson Rockefeller, William Paley, Andre Meyer, and John Hay Whitney to equitably divide up the collection.
        - Pissarro, Camille, 1957-1988 (Box 75, Folder 3)
        - Pollard, J., 1930-1962 (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - Powers, Richard Gorman, 1952 (Box 75, Folder 5)
        - Redon, Odilon, 1959-1982 (Box 75, Folder 6)
        - Reeves, Richard, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 7)
        - Rembrandt, van Rijn, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 8)
        - Renoir, Pierre, 1946-1992 (Box 75, Folder 9-12)
        - Rodin, Auguste, 1955-1985 (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - Rouault, Georges, 1951-1961 (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - Rousseau, Henri, 1949-1994 (Box 76, Folder 3)
        - Rousseau, Théodore, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 4)
        - Sargent, John Singer, 1950-1997 (Box 76, Folder 5-7)
        - Sartorius, Francis, John F., and J. N., 1955-1962 (Box 76, Folder 8)
        - Schwitters, Kurt, 1969-1982 (Box 76, Folder 9)
        - Seurat, Georges, 1950-1983 (Box 76, Folder 10-11)
        - Seymour, A., James, and Joseph, 1929-1959 (Box 77, Folder 1)
        - Shahn, Ben, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 2)
        - Sheeler, Charles, 1947-1950, 1983 (Box 77, Folder 3)
        - Signac, Paul, 1949-1953 (Box 77, Folder 4)
        - Speradio, Cevelli, 1960-1961 (Box 77, Folder 5)
        - Stuart, Gilbert, 1930, 1940, 1946, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 6)
        - Stubbs, George, 1958 (Box 77, Folder 7)
        - Stull, Henry, 1934-1989 (Box 77, Folder 8)
        - Sully, Thomas, 1959-1960 (Box 77, Folder 9)
        - Summers, Carol, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 10)
        - Tamayo, Rufino, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 11)
        - Tate, Arthur F. or John P., 1930 (Box 77, Folder 12)
        - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1933, 1950, 1957 (Box 77, Folder 13)
        - Tissot, James J., 1961 (Box 77, Folder 14)
        - Tooker, George, 1951 (Box 77, Folder 15)
        - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1956-1997 (Box 77, Folder 16-18)
        - Tresor, Nison, 1957 (Box 77, Folder 19)
        - Troye, Edward, 1931 (Box 77, Folder 20)
        - Utrillo, Maurice, 1953-1960 (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Van Dongen, Kees, 1960 (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1947-1998 (Box 78, Folder 3)
        - Van Rysselberghe, Théo, 1956-1957 (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Vervloet, F., 1958 (Box 78, Folder 5)
        - Vlaminck, Maurice de, 1955, 1974-1975 (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - Vuillard, Edouard, 1948-1962 (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Walton, Henry, 1967-1968 (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - Warnecke, Heinz, 1931 (Box 78, Folder 9)
        - Whistler, James, 1928-1983 (Box 78, Folder 10)
        - Wolstenholme, D., 1939 (Box 78, Folder 11)
        - Wyeth, Andrew, 1972-1993 (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - Wyeth, James, 1966 (Box 78, Folder 13)
        - Zerbe, Karl, 1948 (Box 78, Folder 14)
        - Unknown, 1946, 1960, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - Books and manuscripts, 1927-1977 (Box 79, Folder 1-4a)
        Folder 4a contains a draft and manuscript copy of "Tom Fool at Jamaica" by Marianne Moore, given to John Hay Whitney by the author.
      - Cartoons and sketches, 1962, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
        Many of the cartoons appeared in the New Yorker
        - Oversize (Box 396, Folder 3)
      - Decorative arts, 1994-1995
        Contains lists of itemized purchases and five volumes: I. Decorative Smalls, II. House and Garden Furnishings, III. Tableware, IV. Textiles, V. Americana/Folk Art.
        - Itemized purchases (Box 80, Folder 1)
        - I. Decorative Smalls (Box 80, Folder 2-4)
        - II. House and Garden Furnishings (Box 80, Folder 5-6)
        - II. House and Garden Furnishings (Box 81, Folder 1)
        - III. Tableware (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
        - IV. Textiles (Box 81, Folder 4-5)
        - V. Americana/Folk Art (Box 81, Folder 6-7)
      - Disposition of fine art, 1958-1994 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
      - Gifts from John Hay Whitney, 1933-1955 (Box 82, Folder 3-4)
      - Invoices, 1968-1970 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Jewelery
        - Appraisals, 1975-1993 (Box 82, Folder 6)
        - Inventory, Circa 1980-1990 (Box 83, Folder 1-6)
        - Inventory (continued), Circa 1980-1990 (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
        - Invoices, 1967-1978 (Box 84, Folder 3)
        - Jewels from the Estate of Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1998 (Box 84, Folder 4)
          Published by Sotheby's, this auction catalogue contains information about jewelry offered at auction in 1998.
        - Magnificent Jewels, 1999 (Box 84, Folder 5)
        - Purchases, 1941-1995, undated (Box 85, Folder 1-9)
      - LaFarge, John (consultant), 1987-1990 (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
      - Loan Requests
        - Granted
          - 1975-1978 (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
          - 1980-1989 (Box 88, Folder 1-6)
          - 1990-1995 (Box 89, Folder 1-5)
        - Refused, 1997-1998 (Box 89, Folder 6-8)
      - Minor works (catalog cards), A-Z, Undated (Box 90, Folder 1-24)
        Arranged alphabetically by artist.
      - Museums
        - National Gallery of Art
          Includes logistical material about the 1983 John Hay Whitney collection exhibition.
          - General, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 91, Folder 2-3)
          - Dinners, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 4)
        - National Museum of Racing, Whitney Equestrian art exhibition
          - General, 1989 (Box 91, Folder 5)
          - Photographs, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 1)
        - Tate Gallery, 1959-1960 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Paintings
        - Disclaimed
          - Catalog cards, Undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 93, Folder 2)
        - Lost (catalog cards), Undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
        - Offers declined
          - 1931-1950 (Box 93, Folder 4)
          - 1950-1954 (Box 93, Folder 5)
          - 1954-1960 (Box 93, Folder 6)
          - 1966-1991 (Box 93, Folder 7)
        - List of paintings purchased by Betsey Cushing Whitney, report for Carter, Ledyard and Milburn, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 1)
        - Sold, 1950-1955 (Box 94, Folder 2)
        - Uncatalogued (catalog cards), Undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous (catalog cards), Undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - Other art work (catalog cards), Undated (Box 95, Folder 1-5)
      - Press clippings, 1950-1952 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Properties
        - London
          - General (catalog cards), 1957, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
          - Decorative arts, Circa 1950-1960 (Box 95, Folder 8-9)
        - Beekman Place, New York, New York (catalog cards), Undated (Box 95, Folder 10-11)
        - Greenwood, Thomasville, Georgia (catalog cards), Undated (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
        - Saratoga Springs, New York (catalog cards), Undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - Reproduction requests
        - Declined, 1984-1998 (Box 96, Folder 4)
        - Granted
          - 1975-1985 (Box 97, Folder 1-9)
          - 1986-1998 (Box 98, Folder 1-7)
      - Restorations, miscellaneous, 1984-1993 (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Rewald, John (correspondence)
        - General, 1949-1981 (Box 99, Folder 2)
        - Tate Gallery Exhibition, 1960-1961 (Box 99, Folder 3-4)
        - United States Arts Advisory panel (regarding John Hay Whitney's estate), 1982-1984 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Financial files
      - Companies
        - Atrato Company, 1929, 1931 (Box 100, Folder 1)
        - Beckhampton Limited
          New York corporation for race horses in the United Kingdom.